<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Index on Nicholas Yek</title><link>https://nichyjt.github.io/</link><description>Recent content in Index on Nicholas Yek</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-sg</language><copyright>Nicholas Yek</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 May 2021 09:49:37 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nichyjt.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Lab reports - Optimizing for readability</title><link>https://nichyjt.github.io/teaching/cg1111a/lab_reports/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nichyjt.github.io/teaching/cg1111a/lab_reports/</guid><description>Lab Reports and University The purpose In my opinion&amp;hellip; of the Lab report is not only for the teaching team to check your understanding of the material but also for you to consolidate your learning and also practice organizing your thoughts on paper (or digital paper&amp;hellip;) in a structured way.
You need to get used to writing. Lab reports, and by extension, academic writing, are the bread and butter of the academic world, even for an undergraduate.</description></item><item><title>Welcome to Computer Engineering</title><link>https://nichyjt.github.io/teaching/cg1111a/welcome/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nichyjt.github.io/teaching/cg1111a/welcome/</guid><description>Welcome! Hello and welcome to CG1111A! 🙌
Congratulations on getting into Computer Engineering! 🎉
It was NOT easy getting here. Our IGP is pretty darn high.
Your academic career will see you touch MANY aspects of the computing world. You will explore a fair bit of the Computing world, from the lower levels e.g. Logic gates, transistors&amp;hellip; of abstraction to the higher levels e.g. Algorithms, machine learning .
Your first year here will be as fulfilling as it is challenging.</description></item><item><title>Finding Big O from non-standard recurrence relations without master method</title><link>https://nichyjt.github.io/essays/2023/recurrence/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nichyjt.github.io/essays/2023/recurrence/</guid><description>A friend taking their data structures and algorithms (DSA) class asked me a question about recurrence relations. Consider this:
$ \text{Find } O(T(n)), \text{where} ~ T(n) = 3T(\frac{2}{3}n) $
This was derived from pseudocode where 3 recursive calls are made per function call, each splitting the subproblem into (2/3) N.
Nevermind the practicality, its a DSA course after all.
It doesn&amp;rsquo;t fit any of the common recurrence relations, so the convo went something like this:</description></item><item><title>Recovering Linux from initramfs</title><link>https://nichyjt.github.io/essays/2022/initramfs/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nichyjt.github.io/essays/2022/initramfs/</guid><description>You turned on your Linux machine and are greeted by a very scary looking terminal. You&amp;rsquo;ve booted into busybox and are in initramfs. How do I fix this?
initramfs, Image src: askubuntu question Very rarely, memory can get corrupted on your Linux machine. When that happens, you boot into the terminal above. The fix is a simple 1 line command using the fsck built-in tool.
Before using fsck, you need to identify which hard disk stores your working data.</description></item><item><title>How to choose which OS to boot into with systemd-boot</title><link>https://nichyjt.github.io/essays/2022/popos_choose_os/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nichyjt.github.io/essays/2022/popos_choose_os/</guid><description>You are a POP!_OS user or use systemd-boot, and want this screen to pop up when you boot.
systemd-boot menu, Image src: freedesktop.org This guide is for you.
POP_OS was not configured to have the boot menu come up so there is a bit of settings config required.
Option 1: Hold spacebar When you boot, hold spacebar and the menu should show up. Arrow keys to select your boot entry to and press enter to boot into it.</description></item><item><title>FindNUS :telescope:</title><link>https://nichyjt.github.io/projects/findnus/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nichyjt.github.io/projects/findnus/</guid><description>What is FindNUS? FindNUS is a lost and found web application that my pal Jin Xuan and I built over summer 2022.
FindNUS was awarded the highest level of achivement, given to only the top 7% of teams (top 29 of 414 teams) for NUS School of Computing&amp;rsquo;s 2022 iteration of Orbital, an independent software development module.
We built FindNUS because we felt that the current lost and found website in NUS sucks and we could do better.</description></item><item><title>CG2111A - Mod Review</title><link>https://nichyjt.github.io/essays/2022/cg2111a/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nichyjt.github.io/essays/2022/cg2111a/</guid><description>Engineering Principles and Practice 2 (EPP2) CG2111A, aka EPP2 is the highlight module for Computer Engineering freshies.
Personally, it&amp;rsquo;s one of my favourite modules of the semester despite the difficulty. You can expect to build interesting things and learn a whole range of computing topics.
I will be sharing my experience based on the AY 21/22 Semester 2 iteration.
Mapping the maze using Alex&amp;#39;s LiDAR ^ To reiterate, you&amp;rsquo;ll be building cool stuff :)</description></item><item><title>CG1111A - Mod Review</title><link>https://nichyjt.github.io/essays/2022/cg1111a/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nichyjt.github.io/essays/2022/cg1111a/</guid><description>Engineering Principles and Practice 1 (EPP1) CG1111A, aka EPP1 is the very first CEG module NUS Computer Engineering students will be taking.
This is the highlight module for the semester (apart from CS1010), so look forward to it!
I will be sharing my experience based on the AY 21/22 Semester 1 iteration.
CG1111A is conducted in a flipped classroom format where content learning is done asynchronusly and the hands-on learning done via labs and tutorials.</description></item><item><title>SnipNScan :camera:</title><link>https://nichyjt.github.io/projects/snipnscan/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nichyjt.github.io/projects/snipnscan/</guid><description>Image Hell A picture is worth a thousand words - A common adage
Images are a rich source of information. But what worth is that thousand words if I can&amp;rsquo;t extract the actual text inside the images? Let me explain my frustration about images.
Webinar Link Hell Imagine yourself in some online conference. Stare in wonder as the presenter asks you to access some (long-ass) link on their screen share. Extra points if the presenter does not drop the link into chat - good luck typing it into your browser before they move on!</description></item><item><title>Cnake :snake:</title><link>https://nichyjt.github.io/projects/cnake/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nichyjt.github.io/projects/cnake/</guid><description>I thought it would be fun to make a one-shot snake game project to familiarise myself with the ncurses library and play around with some data structures, which led to this ripoff snake game you can find on my GitHub.
If you&amp;rsquo;re interested, you can take a look and perhaps give it a go!
The following sections of this post are just some code discussions for the nerds.
Building Cnake I won&amp;rsquo;t talk too much about the ncurses library and will be writing more about the things I found interesting while building this project, mainly, these questions I had to answer while making the game.</description></item><item><title>Making Linux Home</title><link>https://nichyjt.github.io/essays/2021/linux/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nichyjt.github.io/essays/2021/linux/</guid><description>Linux 🐧 - A Tasty Introduction Are you tired of having useless, suspicious 👀 bloatware being installed on your computer?
Are you looking for a more secure and stable machine out-of-the-box?
Are you a developer that wants to be in better control of your machine?
Perhaps Linux is for you.
What&amp;rsquo;s Linux? Linux refers to the family of Operating Systems (OS) that use the open-source Linux kernel. It may seem like a niche OS, but Linux plays a much larger role in your daily life than you might expect.</description></item><item><title>Sudoku.py</title><link>https://nichyjt.github.io/projects/sudoku/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 May 2021 21:08:04 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://nichyjt.github.io/projects/sudoku/</guid><description>Sudoku Squares are elegant, and frankly, magical.1 With pockets of time being freed up with work from home orders during the COVID-19 pandemic, I picked up Sudoku to fill in the gaps. And man, it&amp;rsquo;s fun solving them - it&amp;rsquo;s cathartic seeing the numbers fall nicely into place.
It&amp;rsquo;s one thing to solve Sudokus, but another to create one.
Out of curiosity, I decided to try and make a fully filled Sudoku Grid by hand.</description></item><item><title>Hey There! :wave:</title><link>https://nichyjt.github.io/homepage/intro/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 May 2021 09:49:37 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://nichyjt.github.io/homepage/intro/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m your host, Nicholas.
Welcome to my little corner of the internet. 🏕️
I waffle on about code &amp;amp; technology.
It ain&amp;rsquo;t much, but it&amp;rsquo;s honest work. 😄
Grab a coffee ☕, relax ⛱️ and enjoy your stay!</description></item><item><title>Computer Engineering (B.Eng Hons), National University of Singapore</title><link>https://nichyjt.github.io/about/experience/nus_ceng/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nichyjt.github.io/about/experience/nus_ceng/</guid><description>Career &amp;amp; Achievements First class honours CAPT A residential college in NUS Honour Roll AY22/23 Top Students for Software Engineering &amp;amp; Object-Oriented Programming (CS2113) Top Students for Engineering Principles and Practice 1 (CG1111A) Teaching &amp;amp; Outreach CG1111A, AY23/24 Semester 1 - Teaching Assistant CG1111A, AY22/23 Semester 1 - Teaching Assistant CDE Open Day 2023 Lab Assistant ECE Open Day 2023 Lab Assistant ECE Lab Tour 2022 Lab Assistant</description></item><item><title>FindNUS :telescope:</title><link>https://nichyjt.github.io/about/projects/findnus/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nichyjt.github.io/about/projects/findnus/</guid><description>Executive Summary:
Awarded the highest level of achivement, given to the top 7% of teams (top 29 of 414 teams) for NUS School of Computing&amp;rsquo;s 2022 iteration of Orbital.
FindNUS is a lost and found web app built during Summer 2022 Orbital. As the backend developer, I built a RESTful API backend using a microservices architecture. Apart from regular CRUD, we also used some NLP and fuzzy searching to help lost people find their lost stuff.</description></item><item><title>New here? README</title><link>https://nichyjt.github.io/teaching/etc/cg1111a_readme/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nichyjt.github.io/teaching/etc/cg1111a_readme/</guid><description>This microsite contains COMPLETELY OPTIONAL supplementary material, tips and explainers for CG1111A coursework for the Academic Year 23/24.
The amount of content I post here will be based on student feedback and academic needs. This page will be (a)periodically updated as the semester progresses!
Note: The contents of this site are NOT officially sanctioned by the ECE department. This is an initiative (and a little project) by me to provide a richer and more targetted learning experience for CG1111A.</description></item><item><title>ResistorPrediction :robot:</title><link>https://nichyjt.github.io/about/projects/resistorprediction/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nichyjt.github.io/about/projects/resistorprediction/</guid><description>Executive Summary:
An experimental attempt to predict resistor values based on pictures of resistors. Powered by machine learning and OpenCV. Achieved up to 60% accuracy in predictions (not exactly production ready).
🔸 Project Link
🚧 Project write-up in progress&amp;hellip;</description></item><item><title>SnipNScan :camera:</title><link>https://nichyjt.github.io/about/projects/snipnscan/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nichyjt.github.io/about/projects/snipnscan/</guid><description>Executive Summary:
Using OpenCV and Tesseract, I built a QR code and text scanner because too much text in this world is embedded in images and are un-copypasteable. Think of images of code.
🔸 Project Blogpost
🔸 Project Link</description></item><item><title>Software Developer Intern</title><link>https://nichyjt.github.io/about/experience/swe_hackertrail/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nichyjt.github.io/about/experience/swe_hackertrail/</guid><description>HackerTrail uses data-driven technology to evaluate and connect software professionals to employers.
Developed new features and many UI changes on the “Assessment Platform” using React, driving a successful UX revamp Analysed competitors and collected user feedback to identify high business value features missing on the platform Built an exploratory backend API using FastAPI to automate company messaging processes Tested with some frontend frameworks to test their SEO effectiveness for the company’s landing page Recommendation by my team lead on my SWE skills.</description></item><item><title>Software Developer Intern</title><link>https://nichyjt.github.io/about/experience/template/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nichyjt.github.io/about/experience/template/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Software Engineer Intern</title><link>https://nichyjt.github.io/about/experience/swe_ncs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nichyjt.github.io/about/experience/swe_ncs/</guid><description>The NCS Things of AI (ToAI) platform is a customizable, end-to-end solution for enterprise &amp;amp; government IOT needs.
Developed customizable data visualisation capabilities by integrating third party APIs into the platform using Angular Generated time-series data visualisation reports for over 32k IOT devices using PostgreSQL and PowerBI Proposed an Agile-based project implementation schedule to support a Tender bid submission Testimonial &amp;amp; Award Nomination by my supervisor, Hsu Yee.</description></item><item><title>Software Engineer Intern</title><link>https://nichyjt.github.io/about/experience/swe_toffs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nichyjt.github.io/about/experience/swe_toffs/</guid><description>TOFFS provides Multi-CDN and cybersecurity solutions for Enterprise networking.
Integrated an Anti-DDoS machine learning (ML) script into network infrastructure, enabling smart IP blacklisting Processed big data (up to 2.5TB) efficiently using concurrent programming to train dozens of ML models Optimised ML training with code refactoring and hardware acceleration, achieving up to 50% reduction in training time Testimonial on my work by Co-Founder Jason Kong.</description></item></channel></rss>