<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Linux on Nicholas Yek</title><link>https://nichyjt.github.io/tags/linux/</link><description>Recent content in Linux on Nicholas Yek</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-sg</language><copyright>Nicholas Yek</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nichyjt.github.io/tags/linux/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>An observation about Docker iptables</title><link>https://nichyjt.github.io/essays/2025/simple_docker_networks/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nichyjt.github.io/essays/2025/simple_docker_networks/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;How do Docker containers talk?&amp;rdquo; is surprisingly interesting. The rabbit hole down containerization is deep. I skim the surface here very quickly. This should not be seen as incredibly technically complete.
Container networks in a nutshell Initialization:
When you install Docker, the docker daemon creates a network interface, (e.g. default is docker0). This network interface is a bridge.
This bridge typically has the &amp;lsquo;gateway&amp;rsquo; ip address &amp;ldquo;X.X.X.1&amp;rdquo;, and by default has a subnet of /16, meaning it can support 2^16 hosts.</description></item><item><title>Docker is not a Virtual Machine</title><link>https://nichyjt.github.io/essays/2025/docker_and_vms/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nichyjt.github.io/essays/2025/docker_and_vms/</guid><description>Docker is not a VM. Neither is it a lightweight VM. But what&amp;rsquo;s the difference? My dockerfile needs an image of an OS (e.g. Ubuntu) to run, and virtual machines (such as VirtualBox) requires an image of an OS to also run, and both produce similar runtime environments for me to run the code in. Don&amp;rsquo;t they do the same thing?
The difference is what resources they virtualize.
Hypervisors &amp;amp; Virtual Machines in 30s Hypervisors (Virtual Machine Managers) emulate hardware resources.</description></item><item><title>Hotswapping kernels like they're keyboard switches</title><link>https://nichyjt.github.io/essays/2024/kernel_duckery/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nichyjt.github.io/essays/2024/kernel_duckery/</guid><description>New Kernels break things. Old Kernels break things. Sometimes in life you want to turn back time to simpler times.
I&amp;rsquo;m taking CS3211 and learning to use thread sanitizer (TSAN) to debug concurrent C++ programs.
Alas, FATAL: ThreadSanitizer: unexpected memory mapping 0x5fb3d2108000-0x5fb3d2129000
Even the simplest of &amp;ldquo;hello world&amp;rdquo; programs (with no concurrency) results in a crash. Pain.
After hours of google-fu, prowling old-school forums and asking around, it turns out to be a kernel issue.</description></item><item><title>Recovering Linux from initramfs</title><link>https://nichyjt.github.io/essays/2022/initramfs/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nichyjt.github.io/essays/2022/initramfs/</guid><description>You turned on your Linux machine and are greeted by a very scary looking terminal. You&amp;rsquo;ve booted into busybox and are in initramfs. How do I fix this?
initramfs, Image src: askubuntu question Very rarely, memory can get corrupted on your Linux machine. When that happens, you boot into the terminal above. The fix is a simple 1 line command using the fsck built-in tool.
Before using fsck, you need to identify which hard disk stores your working data.</description></item><item><title>How to choose which OS to boot into with systemd-boot</title><link>https://nichyjt.github.io/essays/2022/popos_choose_os/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nichyjt.github.io/essays/2022/popos_choose_os/</guid><description>You are a POP!_OS user or use systemd-boot, and want this screen to pop up when you boot.
systemd-boot menu, Image src: freedesktop.org This guide is for you.
POP_OS was not configured to have the boot menu come up so there is a bit of settings config required.
Option 1: Hold spacebar When you boot, hold spacebar and the menu should show up. Arrow keys to select your boot entry to and press enter to boot into it.</description></item><item><title>SnipNScan :camera:</title><link>https://nichyjt.github.io/projects/snipnscan/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nichyjt.github.io/projects/snipnscan/</guid><description>Image Hell A picture is worth a thousand words - A common adage
Images are a rich source of information. But what worth is that thousand words if I can&amp;rsquo;t extract the actual text inside the images? Let me explain my frustration about images.
Webinar Link Hell Imagine yourself in some online conference. Stare in wonder as the presenter asks you to access some (long-ass) link on their screen share.</description></item><item><title>Cnake :snake:</title><link>https://nichyjt.github.io/projects/cnake/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nichyjt.github.io/projects/cnake/</guid><description>I thought it would be fun to make a one-shot snake game project to familiarise myself with the ncurses library and play around with some data structures, which led to this ripoff snake game you can find on my GitHub.
If you&amp;rsquo;re interested, you can take a look and perhaps give it a go!
The following sections of this post are just some code discussions for the nerds.
Building Cnake I won&amp;rsquo;t talk too much about the ncurses library and will be writing more about the things I found interesting while building this project, mainly, these questions I had to answer while making the game.</description></item><item><title>Making Linux Home</title><link>https://nichyjt.github.io/essays/2021/linux/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nichyjt.github.io/essays/2021/linux/</guid><description>Linux 🐧 - A Tasty Introduction Are you tired of having useless, suspicious 👀 bloatware being installed on your computer?
Are you looking for a more secure and stable machine out-of-the-box?
Are you a developer that wants to be in better control of your machine?
Perhaps Linux is for you.
What&amp;rsquo;s Linux? Linux refers to the family of Operating Systems (OS) that use the open-source Linux kernel. It may seem like a niche OS, but Linux plays a much larger role in your daily life than you might expect.</description></item></channel></rss>