<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>About on Nicholas Yek</title><link>https://nichyjt.github.io/about/</link><description>Recent content in About on Nicholas Yek</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-sg</language><copyright>Nicholas Yek</copyright><atom:link href="https://nichyjt.github.io/about/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>B.Eng Hons, Computer Engineering</title><link>https://nichyjt.github.io/about/experience/nus_ceng/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nichyjt.github.io/about/experience/nus_ceng/</guid><description>I was on the HPC team (Team Kent Ridge), stayed far too long on campus in a residential college (CAPT), and took care of community cats on campus 🐱
Complete coursework breakdown.
Awards &amp;amp; Honours GPA 4.7/5.0 (Highest Distinction), Deans' List Focus Area in Communications &amp;amp; Networking 3rd Place in ISC25 Online Student Cluster Competition as part of Team Kent Ridge Top Students, Software Engineering &amp;amp; Object-Oriented Programming (CS2113) Top Students, Engineering Principles and Practice 1 (CG1111A) NUS Computing Honour List of Student Tutors (awarded in 2025) CAPT Honour Roll (awarded in 2023) Teaching Parallel &amp;amp; Concurrent ProgrammingCS3211 &amp;#8203;, Spring 2025 Real-Time Operating SystemsCG2271 &amp;#8203;, Fall 2024 Software Engineering &amp;amp; OOPCS2113 &amp;#8203;, Spring 2024 Engineering Principles &amp;amp; Practice 1CG1111A &amp;#8203;, Fall 2023 &amp;amp; Fall 2022</description></item><item><title>Dioscuri :stars:</title><link>https://nichyjt.github.io/about/projects/dioscuri/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nichyjt.github.io/about/projects/dioscuri/</guid><description>Executive Summary:
Dioscuri is a Gemini protocol (layer 7) implementation in Rust. It functions as a http-to-gemini proxy that brings Gemini websites to any browser of your choice.
Dioscuri&amp;rsquo;s html frontend is highly customizable (a la netscape) with a built-in simple theming framework.
🔸 Project Link and Demo
Nyancat demo (other themes are available):</description></item><item><title>End to End IoT System Development Intern</title><link>https://nichyjt.github.io/about/experience/iot_espressif/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nichyjt.github.io/about/experience/iot_espressif/</guid><description>Espressif Systems develops wireless communication SoCs and cloud solutions to power IoT applications.
Developed a chip power analyzer web application, using ReactJS to visualize data from an ESP32 devices and integrating a custom CNN model built with Keras to classify Bluetooth signals with 95% accuracy Assisted in conducting university workshops, teaching undergraduates how to use advanced ESP32 features</description></item><item><title>FindNUS :telescope:</title><link>https://nichyjt.github.io/about/projects/findnus/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nichyjt.github.io/about/projects/findnus/</guid><description>Executive Summary:
Awarded the highest level of achivement, given to the top 7% of teams (top 29 of 414 teams) for NUS School of Computing&amp;rsquo;s 2022 iteration of Orbital.
FindNUS is a lost and found web app built during Summer 2022 Orbital. As the backend developer, I built a RESTful API backend using a microservices architecture. Apart from regular CRUD, we also used some NLP and fuzzy searching to help lost people find their lost stuff.</description></item><item><title>Site Reliability Engineer (MLOps)</title><link>https://nichyjt.github.io/about/experience/sre_tiktok/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nichyjt.github.io/about/experience/sre_tiktok/</guid><description>0 $ go run career.go</description></item><item><title>SnipNScan :camera:</title><link>https://nichyjt.github.io/about/projects/snipnscan/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nichyjt.github.io/about/projects/snipnscan/</guid><description>Executive Summary:
Using OpenCV and Tesseract, I built a QR code and text scanner because too much text in this world is embedded in images and are un-copypasteable. Think of images of code.
🔸 Project Blogpost
🔸 Project Link</description></item><item><title>Software Developer Intern</title><link>https://nichyjt.github.io/about/experience/template/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nichyjt.github.io/about/experience/template/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Software Developer Intern (Frontend)</title><link>https://nichyjt.github.io/about/experience/swe_hackertrail/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nichyjt.github.io/about/experience/swe_hackertrail/</guid><description>HackerTrail uses data-driven technology to evaluate and connect software professionals to employers.
Spearheaded the migration of the main product platform from Angular to React, rewriting key sections and implementing new features like interactive resizeable components to improve user experience Identified multiple high business value features missing on the main product platform via design thinking methodologies, contributing to the product’s roadmap development Recommendation by my team lead on my SWE skills.</description></item><item><title>Software Engineer Intern (Backend)</title><link>https://nichyjt.github.io/about/experience/swe_toffs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nichyjt.github.io/about/experience/swe_toffs/</guid><description>TOFFS provides Multi-CDN and cybersecurity solutions for Enterprise networking.
Built concurrent data collection pipelines using Go, processing up to 2.5 TB/day of network logs daily Halved training time for anti-DDoS models by optimizing ML training routines and refactoring training pipelines to use GPU acceleration Containerized model deployment with Docker, automated retraining &amp;amp; data update using Bash + cron Testimonial on my work by Co-Founder Jason Kong.</description></item><item><title>Software Engineer Intern (Fullstack)</title><link>https://nichyjt.github.io/about/experience/swe_ncs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nichyjt.github.io/about/experience/swe_ncs/</guid><description>Part of the Things of AI (ToAI) team. The ToAI platform builds E2E IoT device management solutions for enterprise &amp;amp; government IoT needs.
Developed Kubernetes cluster deployments to support a planned platform migration to use Kubernetes Used AngularJS to integrate enterprise APIs like PowerBI into the in-house IoT edge device management platform, enabling custom dashboard visualisations and wrote optimized SQL queries to generate geospatial reports for 32k+ devices Testimonial &amp;amp; Award Nomination by my supervisor, Hsu Yee.</description></item></channel></rss>