<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>About on Nicholas Yek</title><link>https://nichyjt.github.io/about/</link><description>Recent content in About on Nicholas Yek</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-sg</language><copyright>Nicholas Yek</copyright><atom:link href="https://nichyjt.github.io/about/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>B.Eng, Computer Engineering</title><link>https://nichyjt.github.io/about/experience/nus_ceng/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nichyjt.github.io/about/experience/nus_ceng/</guid><description>I was a member in NUS&amp;rsquo;s High-Performance Computing team (Team Kent Ridge), and stayed too long on campus in a residential college (CAPT).
Competed in ISC Student Cluster Competition 2025 as part of the Team Kent Ridge delegation.
Awards &amp;amp; Honours First Class Honours Deans List (AY23/24 S2) CAPT Honour Roll (AY22/23) Top Students, Software Engineering &amp;amp; Object-Oriented Programming (CS2113) Top Students, Engineering Principles and Practice 1 (CG1111A) Teaching Parallel &amp;amp; Concurrent ProgrammingCS3211 &amp;#8203;, Spring 2025 Real-Time Operating SystemsCG2271 &amp;#8203;, Fall 2024 Software Engineering &amp;amp; OOPCS2113 &amp;#8203;, Spring 2024 Engineering Principles &amp;amp; Practice 1CG1111A &amp;#8203;, Fall 2023 Engineering Principles &amp;amp; Practice 1CG1111A &amp;#8203;, Fall 2022 CDE Open Day 2023 ECE Open Day 2023 ECE Lab Tour 2022 Coursework I&amp;rsquo;ve focused on deepening knowledge on computing systems (parallel, large-scale) and networks.</description></item><item><title>End to End IoT System Development Intern</title><link>https://nichyjt.github.io/about/experience/iot_espressif/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nichyjt.github.io/about/experience/iot_espressif/</guid><description>Espressif Systems develops wireless communication SoCs and cloud solutions to power IoT applications.
Developed an AI-powered “power benchmarker” microsite to benchmark chip power usage from oscilloscope data Trained CNN models with up to 95% accuracy to classify BLE events from oscilloscope data using Keras Streamlined collection of live, event driven data from ESP32 chips using concurrent programming Automated region-of-interest feature extraction from time-series oscilloscope data using sklearn Created an interactive microsite to visualise typical BLE power consumption characteristics on ESP32 chips</description></item><item><title>FindNUS :telescope:</title><link>https://nichyjt.github.io/about/projects/findnus/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nichyjt.github.io/about/projects/findnus/</guid><description>Executive Summary:
Awarded the highest level of achivement, given to the top 7% of teams (top 29 of 414 teams) for NUS School of Computing&amp;rsquo;s 2022 iteration of Orbital.
FindNUS is a lost and found web app built during Summer 2022 Orbital. As the backend developer, I built a RESTful API backend using a microservices architecture. Apart from regular CRUD, we also used some NLP and fuzzy searching to help lost people find their lost stuff.</description></item><item><title>SnipNScan :camera:</title><link>https://nichyjt.github.io/about/projects/snipnscan/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nichyjt.github.io/about/projects/snipnscan/</guid><description>Executive Summary:
Using OpenCV and Tesseract, I built a QR code and text scanner because too much text in this world is embedded in images and are un-copypasteable. Think of images of code.
🔸 Project Blogpost
🔸 Project Link</description></item><item><title>Software Developer Intern</title><link>https://nichyjt.github.io/about/experience/swe_hackertrail/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nichyjt.github.io/about/experience/swe_hackertrail/</guid><description>HackerTrail uses data-driven technology to evaluate and connect software professionals to employers.
Developed new features and extensive UI changes with React, driving a successful revamp on the &amp;ldquo;Assessment Platform&amp;rdquo; product Analysed market competitors and collated user feedback to identify high business value features missing on the assessment platform Built an exploratory backend API using FastAPI to automate messaging pipelines Rapid frontend prototyping to affirm SEO effectiveness for the company’s landing page Recommendation by my team lead on my SWE skills.</description></item><item><title>Software Developer Intern</title><link>https://nichyjt.github.io/about/experience/template/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nichyjt.github.io/about/experience/template/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Software Engineer Intern</title><link>https://nichyjt.github.io/about/experience/swe_ncs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nichyjt.github.io/about/experience/swe_ncs/</guid><description>The Things of AI (ToAI) team builds E2E IoT device management solutions for enterprise &amp;amp; government IoT needs.
Built customizable data visualisation capabilities by integrating external APIs into the platform with Angular Generated time-series data visualisation reports for over 32,000 IoT devices using PostgreSQL and PowerBI Authored an Agile-based project implementation schedule to support a Tender bid submission Testimonial &amp;amp; Award Nomination by my supervisor, Hsu Yee.</description></item><item><title>Software Engineer Intern</title><link>https://nichyjt.github.io/about/experience/swe_toffs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nichyjt.github.io/about/experience/swe_toffs/</guid><description>TOFFS provides Multi-CDN and cybersecurity solutions for Enterprise networking.
Integrated an Anti-DDoS machine learning model into network infrastructure, enabling smart IP blacklisting Automated daily processing of up to 2.5 TB of data efficiently with concurrent programming to prep model training Optimised ML training with code refactoring and hardware acceleration, achieving 50% reduction in training time Testimonial on my work by Co-Founder Jason Kong.</description></item></channel></rss>