<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>About on Nicholas Yek</title><link>https://nichyjt.github.io/about/</link><description>Recent content in About on Nicholas Yek</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-sg</language><copyright>Nicholas Yek</copyright><atom:link href="https://nichyjt.github.io/about/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>B.Eng Hons, Computer Engineering</title><link>https://nichyjt.github.io/about/experience/nus_ceng/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nichyjt.github.io/about/experience/nus_ceng/</guid><description>I was a member in NUS&amp;rsquo;s High-Performance Computing team (Team Kent Ridge), and stayed too long on campus in a residential college (CAPT).
Competed in ISC Student Cluster Competition 2025 as part of the Team Kent Ridge delegation.
Awards &amp;amp; Honours GPA: 4.69/5.0 (Highest Distinction / First Class) Deans' List Focus Area in Communications &amp;amp; Networking Top Students, Software Engineering &amp;amp; Object-Oriented Programming (CS2113) Top Students, Engineering Principles and Practice 1 (CG1111A) CAPT Honour Roll (AY22/23) Teaching Parallel &amp;amp; Concurrent ProgrammingCS3211 &amp;#8203;, Spring 2025 Real-Time Operating SystemsCG2271 &amp;#8203;, Fall 2024 Software Engineering &amp;amp; OOPCS2113 &amp;#8203;, Spring 2024 Engineering Principles &amp;amp; Practice 1CG1111A &amp;#8203;, Fall 2023 Engineering Principles &amp;amp; Practice 1CG1111A &amp;#8203;, Fall 2022 CDE Open Day 2023 ECE Open Day 2023 ECE Lab Tour 2022 Coursework I&amp;rsquo;ve focused on deepening knowledge on computing systems (parallel, large-scale) and networks.</description></item><item><title>End to End IoT System Development Intern</title><link>https://nichyjt.github.io/about/experience/iot_espressif/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nichyjt.github.io/about/experience/iot_espressif/</guid><description>Espressif Systems develops wireless communication SoCs and cloud solutions to power IoT applications.
Developed a smart bluetooth power consumption analyser microsite with React and Keras, which utilises a custom CNN model built from scratch with Keras to classify bluetooth signals with up to 95% accuracy Assisted in conducting university workshops, teaching undergraduates how to use advanced ESP32 features</description></item><item><title>FindNUS :telescope:</title><link>https://nichyjt.github.io/about/projects/findnus/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nichyjt.github.io/about/projects/findnus/</guid><description>Executive Summary:
Awarded the highest level of achivement, given to the top 7% of teams (top 29 of 414 teams) for NUS School of Computing&amp;rsquo;s 2022 iteration of Orbital.
FindNUS is a lost and found web app built during Summer 2022 Orbital. As the backend developer, I built a RESTful API backend using a microservices architecture. Apart from regular CRUD, we also used some NLP and fuzzy searching to help lost people find their lost stuff.</description></item><item><title>SnipNScan :camera:</title><link>https://nichyjt.github.io/about/projects/snipnscan/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nichyjt.github.io/about/projects/snipnscan/</guid><description>Executive Summary:
Using OpenCV and Tesseract, I built a QR code and text scanner because too much text in this world is embedded in images and are un-copypasteable. Think of images of code.
🔸 Project Blogpost
🔸 Project Link</description></item><item><title>Software Developer Intern</title><link>https://nichyjt.github.io/about/experience/swe_hackertrail/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nichyjt.github.io/about/experience/swe_hackertrail/</guid><description>HackerTrail uses data-driven technology to evaluate and connect software professionals to employers.
Rewrote multiple sections of the main product platform in React to support framework migration from Angular Implemented three new user-friendly features on the main product platform, improving user experience Identified multiple high business value features missing on the main product platform via design thinking methodologies, contributing to the product’s roadmap development Recommendation by my team lead on my SWE skills.</description></item><item><title>Software Developer Intern</title><link>https://nichyjt.github.io/about/experience/template/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nichyjt.github.io/about/experience/template/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Software Engineer Intern</title><link>https://nichyjt.github.io/about/experience/swe_ncs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nichyjt.github.io/about/experience/swe_ncs/</guid><description>The Things of AI (ToAI) team builds E2E IoT device management solutions for enterprise &amp;amp; government IoT needs.
Enabled customizable data visualization on a IoT management web app by integrating external APIs into the platform with Angular, allowing users to seamlessly design their own BI dashboards Generated time-series data visualization reports for over 32,000 IoT devices with PostgreSQL and PowerBI Testimonial &amp;amp; Award Nomination by my supervisor, Hsu Yee.</description></item><item><title>Software Engineer Intern</title><link>https://nichyjt.github.io/about/experience/swe_toffs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nichyjt.github.io/about/experience/swe_toffs/</guid><description>TOFFS provides Multi-CDN and cybersecurity solutions for Enterprise networking.
Integrated an Anti-DDoS machine learning model into network infrastructure with Python and Go, enabling smart IP blacklisting which helped protect hundreds of client domains managed by TOFFS Automated data collection of network traffic logs, efficiently processing up to 2.5 TB of data daily with concurrent goroutines to support in-house machine learning projects Optimised machine learning training processes with code refactoring and GPU acceleration, achieving up to 50% reduction in training time Testimonial on my work by Co-Founder Jason Kong.</description></item></channel></rss>