<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>About on Nicholas Yek :waffle:</title><link>https://nichyjt.github.io/about/</link><description>Recent content in About on Nicholas Yek :waffle:</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-sg</language><copyright>Nicholas Yek</copyright><atom:link href="https://nichyjt.github.io/about/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Computer Engineering (BEng), National University of Singapore</title><link>https://nichyjt.github.io/about/experience/nus_ceng/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nichyjt.github.io/about/experience/nus_ceng/</guid><description> 2nd Major in Innovation &amp;amp; Design Top Student for CG1111A: Engineering Principles &amp;amp; Practice 1 (EPP1), AY21/22 Semester 1 Teaching Assistant, CG1111A AY22/23 S1</description></item><item><title>HackerTrail, Software Developer Intern</title><link>https://nichyjt.github.io/about/experience/swe_hackertrail/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nichyjt.github.io/about/experience/swe_hackertrail/</guid><description>HackerTrail uses data-driven technology to evaluate tech professionals’ skills and connect them to organisations.
Developed on the candidate evaluation platform as part of a UX/UX revamp effort using React Developed on new features on their employer administration platform using Angular Rapid prototyping of frameworks to appraise SEO efficacy for company’s front-facing website Prototyped a backend API MVP using FastAPI for streamlining messaging pipelines Tech Stack 📚 : React, Angular, Typescript, Hugo, HTML/CSS, Git, Python</description></item><item><title>TOFFS Technologies, Software Engineer</title><link>https://nichyjt.github.io/about/experience/swe_toffs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nichyjt.github.io/about/experience/swe_toffs/</guid><description>TOFFS provides Multi-CDN and cybersecurity solutions for Enterprise networking needs.
Developed a backend application to integrate an Anti-DDoS machine learning solution to TOFFS&amp;rsquo; infra to provide real-time DDoS protection to TOFFS&amp;rsquo; customers Used concurrent programming to process large amounts of data (&amp;gt;2.5TB) to train more than 10k DDoS-Detection machine learning (ML) models tailored to eligible customer domains Optimised model training efficiency (achieved up to 50% reduction in training time) Tech Stack 📚 : Golang, Python, MySQL, Graylogs, REST APIs, Docker, Linux, Git</description></item></channel></rss>