<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>About on Nicholas Yek</title><link>https://nichyjt.github.io/about/</link><description>Recent content in About on Nicholas Yek</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-sg</language><copyright>Nicholas Yek</copyright><atom:link href="https://nichyjt.github.io/about/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Computer Engineering (BEng), National University of Singapore</title><link>https://nichyjt.github.io/about/experience/nus_ceng/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nichyjt.github.io/about/experience/nus_ceng/</guid><description>Academic Career &amp;amp; Achievements 🔸 Top Student for CG1111A, AY21/22 Semester 1
🔸 Teaching Assistant for CG1111A, AY22/23 Semester 1</description></item><item><title>FindNUS :telescope:</title><link>https://nichyjt.github.io/about/projects/findnus/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nichyjt.github.io/about/projects/findnus/</guid><description>Executive Summary:
Awarded the highest level of achivement, given to the top 7% of teams (top 29 of 414 teams) for NUS School of Computing&amp;rsquo;s 2022 iteration of Orbital.
FindNUS is a lost and found web app built during Summer 2022 Orbital. As the backend developer, I built a RESTful API backend using a microservices architecture. Apart from regular CRUD, we also used some NLP and fuzzy searching to help lost people find their lost stuff.</description></item><item><title>HackerTrail, Software Developer Intern</title><link>https://nichyjt.github.io/about/experience/swe_hackertrail/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nichyjt.github.io/about/experience/swe_hackertrail/</guid><description>HackerTrail uses data-driven technology to evaluate and connect software professionals to employers.
Developed on the “Candidate Testing Platform” using React, bringing to production many new features and UI changes as part of a complete UX revamp effort Developed on the &amp;ldquo;Employer Management Platform&amp;rdquo;, extending on existing features using Angular Rapid prototyping of different frameworks to appraise SEO efficacy for company’s public-facing website Prototyped a backend API MVP using FastAPI for streamlining messaging pipelines Technologies: React, Angular, Typescript, Hugo, HTML/CSS, Git, Python</description></item><item><title>SnipNScan :camera:</title><link>https://nichyjt.github.io/about/projects/snipnscan/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nichyjt.github.io/about/projects/snipnscan/</guid><description>Executive Summary:
Using OpenCV and Tesseract, I built a QR code and text scanner because too much text in this world is embedded in images and are un-copypasteable. Think of images of code.
🔸 Project Blogpost
🔸 Project Link</description></item><item><title>TOFFS Technologies, Software Engineer Intern</title><link>https://nichyjt.github.io/about/experience/swe_toffs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nichyjt.github.io/about/experience/swe_toffs/</guid><description>TOFFS provides Multi-CDN and cybersecurity solutions for Enterprise networking.
Integrated an Anti-DDoS machine learning (ML) script into existing workflows to provide real-time DDoS protection to TOFFS&amp;rsquo; customers Processed large amounts of data (approx 2.5 TB worth) to train multiple ML models with concurrent programming Optimized model training efficiency and achieved up to 50% reduction in training time Technologies: Golang, Python, MySQL, Graylogs, REST APIs, Docker, Linux, Git
Testimonial about my time at TOFFS kindly done by Co-Founder Jason Kong.</description></item></channel></rss>