<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>About on Nicholas Yek</title><link>https://nichyjt.github.io/about/</link><description>Recent content in About on Nicholas Yek</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-sg</language><copyright>Nicholas Yek</copyright><atom:link href="https://nichyjt.github.io/about/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Computer Engineering (B.Eng Hons), National University of Singapore</title><link>https://nichyjt.github.io/about/experience/nus_ceng/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nichyjt.github.io/about/experience/nus_ceng/</guid><description>Career &amp;amp; Achievements First class honours CAPT Honour Roll (AY 22/23) Top Students, Software Engineering &amp;amp; Object-Oriented Programming (CS2113) Top Students, Engineering Principles and Practice 1 (CG1111A) Teaching Software Engineering &amp; OOPCS2113 &amp;#8203;, AY23/24 Semester 2 - Teaching Assistant Engrg Principles &amp; Practice 1CG1111A &amp;#8203;, AY23/24 Semester 1 - Teaching Assistant Engrg Principles &amp; Practice 1CG1111A &amp;#8203;, AY22/23 Semester 1 - Teaching Assistant CDE Open Day 2023 Lab Assistant ECE Open Day 2023 Lab Assistant ECE Lab Tour 2022 Lab Assistant</description></item><item><title>End to End IoT System Development Intern</title><link>https://nichyjt.github.io/about/experience/iot_espressif/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nichyjt.github.io/about/experience/iot_espressif/</guid><description>Good things are compiling&amp;hellip;</description></item><item><title>FindNUS :telescope:</title><link>https://nichyjt.github.io/about/projects/findnus/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nichyjt.github.io/about/projects/findnus/</guid><description>Executive Summary:
Awarded the highest level of achivement, given to the top 7% of teams (top 29 of 414 teams) for NUS School of Computing&amp;rsquo;s 2022 iteration of Orbital.
FindNUS is a lost and found web app built during Summer 2022 Orbital. As the backend developer, I built a RESTful API backend using a microservices architecture. Apart from regular CRUD, we also used some NLP and fuzzy searching to help lost people find their lost stuff.</description></item><item><title>ResistorPrediction :robot:</title><link>https://nichyjt.github.io/about/projects/resistorprediction/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nichyjt.github.io/about/projects/resistorprediction/</guid><description>Executive Summary:
An experimental attempt to predict resistor values based on pictures of resistors. Powered by machine learning and OpenCV. Achieved up to 60% accuracy in predictions (not exactly production ready).
🔸 Project Link
🚧 Project write-up in progress&amp;hellip;</description></item><item><title>SnipNScan :camera:</title><link>https://nichyjt.github.io/about/projects/snipnscan/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nichyjt.github.io/about/projects/snipnscan/</guid><description>Executive Summary:
Using OpenCV and Tesseract, I built a QR code and text scanner because too much text in this world is embedded in images and are un-copypasteable. Think of images of code.
🔸 Project Blogpost
🔸 Project Link</description></item><item><title>Software Developer Intern</title><link>https://nichyjt.github.io/about/experience/swe_hackertrail/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nichyjt.github.io/about/experience/swe_hackertrail/</guid><description>HackerTrail uses data-driven technology to evaluate and connect software professionals to employers.
Developed new features and extensive UI changes with React, driving a successful revamp on the &amp;ldquo;Assessment Platform&amp;rdquo; product Analysed market competitors and collated user feedback to identify high business value features missing on the assessment platform Built an exploratory backend API using FastAPI to automate messaging pipelines Rapid frontend prototyping to affirm SEO effectiveness for the company’s landing page Recommendation by my team lead on my SWE skills.</description></item><item><title>Software Developer Intern</title><link>https://nichyjt.github.io/about/experience/template/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nichyjt.github.io/about/experience/template/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Software Engineer Intern</title><link>https://nichyjt.github.io/about/experience/swe_ncs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nichyjt.github.io/about/experience/swe_ncs/</guid><description>The NCS Things of AI (ToAI) platform is a customizable, end-to-end solution for enterprise &amp;amp; government IOT needs.
Built customizable IOT data visualisation features with third party APIs using Angular Created time-series data reports for over 32k IOT devices using PostgreSQL and PowerBI Proposed an Agile-based project implementation schedule to support a Tender bid submission Testimonial &amp;amp; Award Nomination by my supervisor, Hsu Yee.</description></item><item><title>Software Engineer Intern</title><link>https://nichyjt.github.io/about/experience/swe_toffs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nichyjt.github.io/about/experience/swe_toffs/</guid><description>TOFFS provides Multi-CDN and cybersecurity solutions for Enterprise networking.
Integrated an Anti-DDoS machine learning (ML) script into network infrastructure, enabling smart IP blacklisting Automated daily pre-processing of up to 2.5 TB of data efficiently with concurrent programming to prep model training Optimised ML training with code refactoring and hardware acceleration, achieving 50% reduction in training time Testimonial on my work by Co-Founder Jason Kong.</description></item></channel></rss>