<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Essay on Nicholas Yek</title><link>https://nichyjt.github.io/tags/essay/</link><description>Recent content in Essay on Nicholas Yek</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-sg</language><copyright>Nicholas Yek</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nichyjt.github.io/tags/essay/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Finding Big O from non-standard recurrence relations without master method</title><link>https://nichyjt.github.io/essays/2023/recurrence/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nichyjt.github.io/essays/2023/recurrence/</guid><description>A friend taking their data structures and algorithms (DSA) class asked me a question about recurrence relations. Consider this:
$ \text{Find } O(T(n)), \text{where} ~ T(n) = 3T(\frac{2}{3}n) $
This was derived from pseudocode where 3 recursive calls are made per function call, each splitting the subproblem into (2/3) N.
Nevermind the practicality, its a DSA course after all.
It doesn&amp;rsquo;t fit any of the common recurrence relations, so the convo went something like this:</description></item><item><title>CG2111A - Mod Review</title><link>https://nichyjt.github.io/essays/2022/cg2111a/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nichyjt.github.io/essays/2022/cg2111a/</guid><description>Engineering Principles and Practice 2 (EPP2) CG2111A, aka EPP2 is the highlight module for Computer Engineering freshies.
Personally, it&amp;rsquo;s one of my favourite modules of the semester despite the difficulty. You can expect to build interesting things and learn a whole range of computing topics.
I will be sharing my experience based on the AY 21/22 Semester 2 iteration.
Mapping the maze using Alex&amp;#39;s LiDAR ^ To reiterate, you&amp;rsquo;ll be building cool stuff :)</description></item><item><title>CG1111A - Mod Review</title><link>https://nichyjt.github.io/essays/2022/cg1111a/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nichyjt.github.io/essays/2022/cg1111a/</guid><description>Engineering Principles and Practice 1 (EPP1) CG1111A, aka EPP1 is the very first CEG module NUS Computer Engineering students will be taking.
This is the highlight module for the semester (apart from CS1010), so look forward to it!
I will be sharing my experience based on the AY 21/22 Semester 1 iteration.
CG1111A is conducted in a flipped classroom format where content learning is done asynchronusly and the hands-on learning done via labs and tutorials.</description></item><item><title>Making Linux Home</title><link>https://nichyjt.github.io/essays/2021/linux/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nichyjt.github.io/essays/2021/linux/</guid><description>Linux 🐧 - A Tasty Introduction Are you tired of having useless, suspicious 👀 bloatware being installed on your computer?
Are you looking for a more secure and stable machine out-of-the-box?
Are you a developer that wants to be in better control of your machine?
Perhaps Linux is for you.
What&amp;rsquo;s Linux? Linux refers to the family of Operating Systems (OS) that use the open-source Linux kernel. It may seem like a niche OS, but Linux plays a much larger role in your daily life than you might expect.</description></item></channel></rss>